

Edmonton, Canada

🛮 (587) 879-4626 | 🗷 tkuipers123@gmail.com | 🌴 tkuipers.ca | 🖸 tkuipers | 🛅 tyler-kuipers | 🎓 Tyler Kuipers

Summary.

I am a Software Developer with hands-on experience in many facets of software development. I am an enthusiastic, supportive team player dedicated to efficiently solving problems. I have experience in full-stack development and have also led teams, helped mentor junior developers, and performed well individually.

Work Experience

Arterys Inc. Calgary, Alberta (Remote)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Aug 2022 - Present

I work as a Software Developer Arterys on their core platform. Responsibilities include the following:

- Various bug fixes and feature enhancements throughout the product. (Typescript, NodeJS)
- Working to lower turn-around-time on results of our AI algorithms. (AWS, Chef, Redis)
- Code reviewing and testing various patches submitted by other developers. (Git, GitHub)
- Helping new developers learn how to work and develop on our product suite.
- · Monitor logs and other health checking platforms for problems before clients are impacted. (Elastic, FullStory, Kibana)

Alberta Motor Association

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SOFTWARE TEAM LEAD

Jun 2018 - Feb 2021 | Feb 2021 - Aug 2022

I worked as a Software Developer for AMA's Insurance Division, doing development on its core insurance product. Responsibilities included the following:

- Leading a team of developers working on the AMA's PolicyCenter implementation.
- Leading another team contributing to an organization-wide standards initiative.
- Performing scrum master responsibilities to increase team efficiency.
- Suggesting and facilitating improvement ideas brought forward by the insurance development team.

I have also brought success to our department in the following ways:

- Led an initiative designing and programming the test framework. It has led to a sharp reduction in bugs throughout following projects.
- Planned and implemented the solutions used for online payment on AMA's website, utilizing third-party APIs and Guidewire.
- Supported my team through knowledge transfer, guidance, and open dialogue.
- Participated in upgrade assessment with Guidewire to determine the scope and amount of work required to upgrade AMA's instance of Guidewire to the cloud.

Pleasant Solutions Edmonton, Alberta

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

I worked as a full-stack developer on projects highly customized to the client's needs.

- Daily work was completed in C# .NET, heavily utilizing an MVC design pattern.
- · Gained experience in leadership roles for small projects.
- TDD methodologies were used to complete tasks.
- Front-end work was completed in a mix of C# and HTML/JS using C# Razor.
- Created the HMI for a concrete distribution plant. This project used C# to integrate with PLC ladder logic to report on and control a concrete distribution center.

Lockheed Martin Canada Halifax, Nova Scotia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ASSOCIATE

Worked as an associate software engineer developing software to be used in CMS 330.

- Contributed to an internal research project, implementing a Data Fusion module for use with Combat Management Systems.
- Worked to develop software modules responsible for the management and status of various underwater sensors.
- · Worked in an Agile SCRUM environment.
- · Completed daily work using TDD methodologies.

The King's University

Edmonton, Alberta

Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

 ${\sf Software\ Developer/Research\ Assistant}$

May 2014 - Sep 2016

Worked as a full stack developer; designed and implemented an approach to dynamically reference items both spatially and temporally.

- Designed and built a website that researchers could input information into; viewers could see the data and explore it.
- Researched the method utilized and authored an undergraduate thesis documenting my contribution to the Edmonton River Atlas
 Website
- Primarily advanced skills in PHP, HTML, JavaScript and jQuery, PostgreSQL, and PostGIS.



Stock Guesser

This project pulls news articles and stock information about specific tickers from the internet nightly. It runs the article through IBM's tone analyzer and uses the result to train a small neural network. The network attempts to correlate the tone of a particular article to a stock's outcome over the next day. A user is then able to enter a stock ticker, and the program will pull the most recent article it can find for that company, and attempt to predict whether the stock will go up or down the next day.

It is implemented in python, using GitHub actions to train and deploy the program to EC2 and Lambdas on AWS weekly. You can check it out at https://tkuipers.ca

Education

Athabasca UniversityEdmonton, AlbertaCMPT 501May 2021 - Present

I am taking some master's courses to keep learning and stay updated with software development methodologies.

The King's UniversityEdmonton, AlbertaB.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCESep 2012 - Dec 2016